Okay, so we are doing Socrates and Plato today.
好的，我们今天讲苏格拉底和柏拉图。
Last class we did Greek theater.
好的，上一节课我们做了希腓剧场。
And remember I said that Aeschylus, Sophocles,
再来记得我说过的那句“古希腓”??
and Eupodes, they're really prophets of democracy.
和尤普德斯，他们是古典的民主先知。
They see themselves as teachers who teach Athenians
他们以此为名，给古典里的古典…??…
how to practice democracy.
此时……??…
We also said that there are three major benefits
我们也说过，民主有三大优势。第一大优势是王者有好。
to democracy. The first major benefit is kings are bad.
OK? 好 ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? ?? 古……??…
Okay? Kings have hubris and hubris creates all sorts of problems.
…
So remember in the play, Antigone, by Sophocles,
在剧中记得，苏普·安提戈尼的《安提戈尼》里…??…
the king Creon sentences Antigone to death even
??…
though he was unjust and that was because of hubris.
Second major benefit of democracy is it is a gift from the gods
第二个大????????????????????????????????????????????????????
that teaches citizens individual responsibility and accountability.
?
Okay, so remember that in Eurostia,
Aeschylus told us that
???
democracy is a gift from Athena in order to promote justice
and truth in the world. And
???
the third major benefit is democracy is
第三个主要好处是民主是
really the best way to promote justice
真正的...??
and truth in the world.
??
If citizens come together
如果公民聚在一起
and they deliberate and act
若干事…
with in good faith, then the world will be a better place.
??
Okay? So that is the argument from the playwrights of Athens.
好的？ 好吧！
Now, obviously there are people who disagree with this perspective.
...
And one of the most famous opponents of democracy
is Socrates.
是苏格拉底。
Socrates lived during the time of
...
the golden age of Pericles in Athens
佩里克利斯在雅典的黄金时代
and he was a very vocal opponent.
和他很有声响的古典
He was a very vocal opponent of democracy for the following reason.
他是上述原因的极其响的古典。
In order to practice democracy properly, people need to access the truth.
在此时刻…
But to access the truth, you need to have reason.
但要获取真理，你需要有理性。
And his argument was that most people are not capable
translationt
of exercising reason in their thinking.
of 1…
Okay? And to prove this,
? 1?
every day he would be sitting outside the Agora,
每天在阿格罗外坐着
which is the marketplace of Athens.
And this is where the! everyone came together.
和这就是...！每个...！
And he would spend all day arguing with people in something called a psychotic dialogue
...我...??
and showing the flaws in your reasoning.
...??
Okay? Showing you why you don't really understand the world
好的？展示给你看，为什么我方才会有点儿…
when you think you do.
好的，方……………
Okay? Trying to prove that you are ignorant.
先前…………
Okay? So let me give you a demonstration of what Socrates did.
...
Okay? So give me a statement that is fundamentally,
OK? 先给我...??
and inherently true. Give me a statement
...
that you think is fundamentally, and inherently true.
那 好 好 ...
The earth is a sphere, right?
...
The earth is a sphere.
And so, this is a statement that we think is true, right?
...
And so what Socrates would do is, he would slowly
and methodologically expose the flaws in this statement.
...
Okay? So the first question for you is,
what is a sphere? Explain what a sphere is.
...
Okay, so you have three -dimensional round -shaped energy, okay?
And give me an example of a sphere.
...
A ball, right? So you're saying the earth is like a ball.
一个球，没错吧？于是你说地球是个球形。
Is that correct? It's all round.
是的，回到球形的那点！
Okay? And how do you know the statement is true?
OK? 先后? 先后??
Who told you this? I mean,
]}We need to translate cues [61] and [62] into Simplified Chinese. Provide JSON array translations. Ensure each translation string may contain at most one newline. Use natural Chinese. Let's translate: [61]
you can know a ball is a sphere because you hold it in your hand, right?
你可以用手握住球体来判断它是球形的吧？
But you're not a god. You don't hold the earth in your hand.
你不必再手握球球??
So how do you know it's true? Anyway,
???
I can go on like this, obviously, for a very long time.
]}We need to translate cues [65] and [66] into Simplified Chinese. ProvideJSON array translations. The previous context? Let's read cues. We have [65]
But I'm going to go on like this, obviously, for a very long time. And so this is what Socrates did.
翻译...????????????????…
And this is what he called a psychotic dialogue.
...…………..??…..…………………………..………
And actually, we still use this in many different places, like, for example, law school.
翻译成...??…...??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…
So in American law schools, if you have,
??…..??…..??…..??…..??...??..??……..??…..??………??…??…??…
if you ever make the stupid mistake of ever applying to law school and
?
you get into law school, they will teach you using the psychotic dialogue.
Okay? But the idea is to show the flaws in your reasoning.
OK? 但要点是把…………………………………………………
And obviously, if you get an argument from Socrates,
?????..??..??..…………………………………………………………………………??……………………………??……..??……………………………………??………??……………………………??…...??..??…………………………………………??……………??………?
you come out as a very mad person.
你可以在此时的雅典里看到他…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??……??…??…??…??…??…??……??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…??…???
Okay? So the representation is this. The representation of Socrates in Athens during this time was he was either a,
??…??…??…??…??…???
you could either see him as a bully, okay?
你可以把他当作一个霸气的人，好的？
He was an intellectual bully.
他是个…
Or he was a clown.
或他是个小丑人。
Or the most common understanding of Socrates was he was a trickster.
或他在此时的最常见的说法是：他是个小丑人。
Okay? He tricked you into making statements
Okay? He tricked youinto making statements
that were illogical because fundamentally, language
..
does not capture the truth.
不再捕捉真相。
Okay? Language is just a convention we have to make statements that are illogical.
好的，语言只要…
Socrates was not meant to, in order for us to communicate.
索福尔斯特不只是为了让我们交流而存在。
But it's not meant to reflect reality. Okay?
索福尔斯特不必然是为了给我方…
And Socrates was exposing the fundamental flaws in our language system.
So any questions about this so far?
现在还有什么问题吗？
All right. So to give you a sense of how Athenians thought about Socrates at
...
that time, let me describe to you a play by Erzophanes.
那时，我来给你们介绍一出埃尔佐法恩的戏剧。
Okay? Erzophanes. Okay.
好的，埃尔佐法恩？
So, Erzophanes was a very famous satirist in Athens.
在埃尔佐法恩的时代，...
And he made fun of all the very famous individuals of Athens,
]}We need to output JSON with translations array of two strings. The cues: [92]
including Pericles, who as we said was the de facto king of Athens at this time,
...???????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
but also Cleon, who
...???????????????????????????????????????
replaced Pericles as the leader of Athens.
...???...??...??...??...??...??...??...??
He also made fun of Socrates.
...??...??...??...???
Okay? And the play is called, The Clouds.
So the play was produced in 423 BCE,
?
and the play was called The Clouds.
...?????????...????...??????
So let me first explain the plot of The Clouds, and then we will interpret what it meant.
...??????...???
Okay? So in The Clouds, there's this Athenian farmer,
好的？在《云雾》里，有一位雅典农夫，
a normal citizen, and he's in a lot of trouble
正常的普通民众，且他正好在百花之中。
because his wife spends a lot of money.
因为他妻子百花花花花花花…
So he owes a lot of money to creditors.
他欠了很多钱给债主们。
And his creditors are banging at the door and demanding their money back.
他债主们的回到回到…
So he comes up with this plan.
他回到…
He has a plan to get rid of his debts.
他有个计划摆脱债务。
There's a school called a thinkery.
有个叫“思考院”之学堂。
Okay? And it's run by a man named Socrates.
好的，且可用来回到…
The thinkery proposes to teach you reason,
译文1
logic, truth, so that you can go and deceive jurors.
译者翻译后...??????????????????????????????????????????翻译...???????????????????????????????????
Okay? You can basically go and manipulate people and
??????????????????…
deceive them in a trial to get out of your debts.
译文1
So he wants to send his son to...
译文2
to the thinkery to learn how to lie to juries.
译视频
His son, who is a playboy, refuses
他的儿子是个花花公子，随便去吧！
because he says that Socrates, he's a cheat, he's a liar, he's a fraud.
他在说…………………
I refuse to go. The man decides to check out the thinkery by himself.
先前…………………
He goes in, and he sees Socrates,
他去到达里亚里去看见了苏格拉斯，
okay, hanging from a basket from the ceiling.
他在此处……………………………
And the man's curious, like, what are you doing up there?
…………??…????…………
And Socrates says, well, from up there.
...
Up here, I have a clearer and higher vision of the world.
I can access truth better.
...
Also from here, I can draw inspiration from the clouds, who are the true gods.
也从这里，我可以从云中汲取灵感，云是那真正的神。
Okay? Not Zeus, not Heracles.
好的，云从哪?
The clouds are the true gods.
云从…………
And they're the ones who
他们是那里的...
give me inspiration to come up with all these brilliant ideas.
...
Okay? So the man and Socrates has...
They have a very long conversation, and
他们有很长的对话，且…
he's completely convinced Socrates is a...
他完全肯定…
Sage, okay? He's a philosopher.
…
He runs back, and he tells his son,
他跑回去，告诉他儿子，
you must go enroll in the thinkery and learn from Socrates.
他要去报名参加学堂并从苏格拉底学到…
Okay? So the son decides this is the path of least resistance.
...
He goes to the thinkery, and he becomes Socrates' student.
他去学堂，成为苏格拉底的学生。
Meanwhile, the man's creditors are banging on the door and
与此同时，先生 ………………… …
saying to him, where is my money?
他在此时…
And the man says...
他又说…
The man is now going to use all the tricks that Socrates taught him.
他现在用苏格拉底教他的全套技巧
Okay? So what he says is, I don't owe you any money.
...
And then the creditor says,
又是...
you swore by Zeus that you would pay me back.
The man says, oh, guess what?
又是...
Zeus doesn't exist.
泽乌斯不存在。
Okay? He's not a god.
好的？他不是神。
So I swore an oath to nothing.
于是我发誓于无物。
Therefore, I owe you nothing.
因此，我欠你一分钱。
The creditor obviously gets angry, and he leaves.
债主显然很忙，回到后又回到！
Okay? Now, the son comes back.
先前的??
And he... And the first thing he does is start beating his father.
他...他先把父亲揍了起来。
And the father is like, why are you beating me, son?
父亲说：我回到??
And then the son says, Socrates taught me to beat you.
先后??
And the father's like, what?
和父亲说，什么？
He didn't... Why is he teaching you that?
他不…我想要点儿…
And the son says, he taught me justice.
他把我说成了…
Now, when I was young, did you beat me?
现在我还小的时候，你打我了吗？
The father says, yes, of course I beat you, because you were a naughty boy.
父亲说：我回…
And then the son says, therefore, I can now beat you, because you're a naughty father.
先后…
You're a naughty father.
你是个小伙子。
You're a naughty father. You're a naughty father. You're a naughty father.
你是个小伙子，回到回到！
You're a naughty father. You're a naughty father.
他回到！
你是个小伙子。你是个小伙子。
You're a naughty father. You're a naughty father.
你是个小伙号…
You're a naughty father.
...
You're a naughty father. You're a naughty father.
你是个小伙子。你是个小伙子。
You're a
你是个小伙子。
naughty father.
The pagans didn't think much of Socrates. He worships the clouds, right, which is nothing.
平信徒对苏格拉底并不算什么， 他把他自己又大写的“云”来回去。 只要好好…
So what they're saying is Socrates makes things out of thin air.
他把……
He's just a fraud, he's a manipulator, he's a liar.
他……
But Socrates did have a lot of fans,
但苏格拉底确实有很多粉丝，
specifically people who really hated democracy.
具体是那种人，才会去做…
And so the people who really hated democracy were the children of the rich.
…
These were aristocrats, born into the wealthiest,
这些人是贵族，出生在雅典最富裕的贵族家族中，
most noble aristocratic families of Athens,
这些人是贵族，出生在雅典最富贵的家族中，
who hated the fact that the normal people thought they were their equals, okay?
So what Socrates did was he taught them basically
于是，苏格拉底所作的就是…
mental or linguistic kung fu, right,
…
to go beat up these commoners who dared to think they're equals.
One of the most famous of Socrates' students included Plato,
...
who we all know. But
also Alcabias, who
...
was one of the wealthiest members of Athenian society.
186. 这是一句…
He actually became leader of Athens as well, okay?
186???????…
So Socrates had his fans,
?…
and because Athens was such a wealthy and open and tolerant society,
......
they allowed Socrates to basically do whatever he wanted.
Until 404 BCE.
......
This was the year
192. 这是一句…
that Athens lost the Peloponnesian War to Sparta, okay?
193. 这句…
And when Athens lost the war, Sparta did not burn Athens down.
194. 这句…
Sparta had the right to burn Athens down, but it did not, okay?
...
Instead, Athens imposed a dictatorship called the Thirty Tyrants.
And the Thirty Tyrants came from
...
the wealthiest families of Athens,
198. 这句…
who also happened to be students of Socrates.
199. 这句…
Socrates did not actually participate in a tyranny.
200. 这句…
Socrates refused to participate in a tyranny, but
索福尔斯不参与暴政，但他有许多学生是这些暴君。
there were many of these tyrants who were Socrates' students.
索福尔斯不再给他人做事，给我…
And they were terrible people.
...
They killed at least 5% of the Athenian population.
他们至少杀死了5%的雅典人。
They stole a lot of wealth.
他们偷了很多财富。
And they were so terrible that ultimately,
他们又是如此之大…
the Athenian people revolted against them
...
and reinstalled their democracy, okay?
So, when the tyranny was overthrown,
...
the Thirty Tyrants were exiled,
三十位暴君被流放，但大多数人获赦免，他们若参与过政权则可赦免。
but most people were given clemency, okay?
三十位暴君被流放，但大多数人获赦命？
They were forgiven if they participated in the regime.
...
Then what happens next is very strange.
然后接下来发生的事很奇怪。
In 399 BCE,
在399年BCE里
Socrates is put on trial.
在此时，苏格拉底斯被送到回归
Remember, this is after the democracy is reinstated.
记得，民主复兴后，
And this is when people who
当时人们在此时
participated in the tyranny were forgiven, okay?
But in 399 BCE,
但在399年BCE里
Socrates was put on trial.
苏格拉底斯被送到回归
And he was put on trial and charged with two crimes.
而且在回归里回归
The first is impiety, okay?
第一点是对神不敬，好的？
Which basically means he was insulting the gods of Athens,
基本上是说他在亚历宫里…
including Zeus, which is what he did in the plague clouds, okay?
...
The second is corrupting the youth of Athens.
翻译1
Okay, basically, miseducating the youth of Athens,
翻译2
which is also what he did in the clouds,
翻译后
okay? So, it almost seems like this entire trial
ok? 这段落后? 先后??
was a cruel joke put on by the people of Athens to teach Socrates a lesson,
?????????????????????????????????????????? 先后?????? ？????????? ??? ??? ????????????????????..????????..?????..???翻??????????????? 先??????????????????????????..?????..???{
okay? Does that make sense?
]}We need to translate cues 228-230. Provide Chinese subtitles. Use line breaks. Provide JSON array. Let's translate. 228:
So, the people of Athens expected Socrates to apologize,
??
make some jokes, be funny, and then all is forgiven, right?
During the trial,
Socrates refused to defend himself.
Socrates 先后??????????????????????????????????????????
What he said was this. I am not a good speaker.
???????????????????????????????????????
I am bad with words.
I'm just a poor person, okay,
??
who comes from a poor family,
来自贫穷家庭的人
who spends every day seeking out the truth.
每天寻找真相的人
I spend all my time seeking out the truth,
我把全部时间都用来寻找真相，思考其一一回到回
thinking about the truth, that I have no time to practice rhetoric.
我把全时光回到回??
I'm not good with words.
我不太好说话
Also, I should not have to defend myself
because you're all capable of reason.
因为你们都能用理性思考。
You're all capable of logic.
Therefore, if you just think for yourself,
因此，若你只用来回…
you will realize I'm not guilty.
...………??…??…??
I have absolutely nothing to do with the 30 tyrants.
??……??…??
I spent all my life trying to help Athens.
我花了一生去为雅典而努力
Therefore, if you're stupid, you will vote me guilty.
我方块块………??…???
If you're stupid, there's nothing I can do about it, okay?
我方块……????
Obviously, the jury was insulted by his speech,
Obviously, the jury wasinsulted by his speech,
and they voted out of 500 people,
和我方块……………………………………………………
280 to 220,
...……………………………………………………
they voted that he is guilty, okay?
他们投票认为他有罪，好吗？
They declared he was guilty of these two charges.
他们宣告他这两项指控已定罪。
Now, as you can see, it's still a pretty close vote, okay?
We have...???
I mean, Socrates was basically being a jerk during the trial,
...
and they still, they voted him guilty, but
和我方块……………………
it was a pretty close trial, 280 to 220.
Now, the second part of the trial is, if you're found guilty,
they have to figure out what your punishment is, okay?
他们需要知道你的处罚是什么？
So, the jury asked Socrates to propose a punishment for his crimes.
...
And then, what Socrates said was,
翻译：
you have found me guilty, and the reason why you found me guilty is
你们已把我放在了...
because I speak the truth.
...
I am a gadfly, okay?
Gadfly. I go around and
...
I point out the nasty truths of Athenian society.
我指出雅典社会的丑闻。
I put a mirror to your face, and
我把镜子放在你们的面前，
I show you your warts, your pimples, your ugliness.
我把...
Therefore, you hate me.
...
But, what I've been doing all my life has been for the good
但我一直以此为准，做了个…
and betterment of Athens.
...
I'm a public servant. I am the most selfless public servant,
我是一名公...
okay? Because I speak the truth,
...
and by showing the truth, I make you a better person.
并且通过展示真相，我让你们成为更好的人。
Therefore, I think a just punishment would be a penchant.
因此我想要点儿…
Okay? You guys should pay me to retire in peace.
...
But, you know what?
但你知道吗？
I'm a generous and forgiving individual.
我是一位慷慷大方的好人！
Therefore, if you don't want to give me a pension, I will understand.
因此我可以给你们…
Therefore, I am willing to pay a small fine, okay?
因此，我愿意支付一点小罚款，好的？
I'll pay a fine, okay?
我会支付一笔小费，好的？
And then, we're good.
然后我们就好啦。
How about that? And again,
怎么样？再来一次，
the Athenian jurors were pissed off, right?
雅典人投票时，算作??
So, they voted to
于是…
condemn him to death by tricking him with a hemlock.
好的，先给我点儿...??
Okay? They basically gave him the death penalty.
好的，...??
After they did so, they came to realize
...
that they were perhaps tricked by Socrates.
那时他们可能被苏格拉底斯骗了。
Okay? Socrates was 70 years old.
好的？苏格拉底斯70岁了。
That's very old for back then, okay?
那时很久以前，算吧？
70 years old was probably the age limit back then.
70岁时，可能是当时的年龄上限。
He really didn't have much to live for.
他真的没什么可活的了。
And here was the opportunity for Socrates to be a martyr for the truth,
他在此时刻…
right? All his life,
右？他一生都在尝试说服人们民主没用。
he's been trying to convince people democracy does not work.
右? 只要他一生都在尝试…
Because people are incapable of reasoning out the truth.
因为人们无法推理真相。
And what this trial shows us is he was correct.
而且…
Right? Does that make sense? So, in many ways,
you can make the argument that for Socrates,
翻译：
this trial was a type of performance art.
...
Okay? He was a performance artist.
OK?
Okay? And so, the people of Athens realized
OK? 这句...??
that they were probably tricked.
翻译：
And they were trying to get out of condemning Socrates to death.
??
But Socrates insisted. And
it came to a point where Socrates was just left alone.
它到达了一个点，苏格拉斯只好像…
And he had to demand to be given a hemlock.
...
And he had to administer the hemlock by himself.
他自己给了他喝的那杯酒。
And so, when he drank it, he died. Okay?
他自己给了那杯酒喝。”
Now, I'm going to give you a little bit of a story. After his death,
现在，我要给你们讲个小故事。之后，苏格拉斯去世后，
Socrates remained an extremely controversial individual in Athens.
苏格拉斯在后续去世后，
And he had a student, Plato, who
And ... ...
was maybe 28, 29 at the time his mentor died.
...
Okay? And he loved Socrates.
好的？他也很喜欢苏格拉斯。
And he committed the rest of his life to restoring
好的，...??
and redeeming the reputation of Socrates.
和赎回苏格拉斯的名声。
So, when he was 40 years old, he founded a school called
当时他在 0? 里…
The Academy. Okay?
翻译1
Which was inspired by the vision of Socrates as a philosopher
翻译2
who sought the truth. In 375 BCE,
翻译??
he wrote a book called The Republic.
他写了一本名为《共和国》的书。
And The Republic is the most famous of Plato's work.
《共和国》是柏拉图的作品中最著名的。
It is arguably the greatest work of Western philosophy.
它可以说是西方哲学的最著名作。
And many today consider The Republic the greatest book ever written.
多位今日认为《共和国》是史上最伟大的著作。
Okay? There are people in this world who have written a lot of great books.
好吧，世界里有些人写过多种大作，但却没能写出《共和国》。”
But they've never read The Republic. And it forever transforms the way they see the world.
“我”??
Okay? It's a life transforming event to read The Republic.
好的？读《共和国》是一件改变人生的事。
And next semester, we will actually read The Republic together.
接下来一学期我们会一起读《共和国》。”
Okay? But let me give you a quick introduction to The Republic.
好的，先给我方块的“方块”??
So, in The Republic, there's a very famous metaphor.
所以，在《共和国》中有一个非常著名的比喻。
And it's called Allegory of the Cave.
而且有个别名叫“咸咸”??
And this is really the most famous
又...
allegory or metaphor or analogy in Western thought, okay?
...
By fall. Nothing comes second to this.
So before I start the allegory of the cave,
...
are there any questions so far about what I've discussed? Anything unclear?
已到此处，先前已讨论的内容有何回顾？
Anything you would like to question or doubt or argue with if I continue with the allegory of the cave?
已在此处………??
Okay? Clear so far?
先前……??
All right. So this is the allegory.
343. 先前...??
Imagine a cave deep under the earth, okay?
]}
There's a cave. Now, in this cave, at the back,
?
there's a large fire that
有一大火光照进这座山洞
shines light into this cave, okay?
有大火光照进山洞里
There are these prisoners who
有大火光照在山里
are chained to the floor,
被链在地面上，
and they're chained so that they cannot move their necks.
被链在地面上并且能链在...??
They can't move around, okay?
...
They can't move. The only thing they can do is steer at a wall, and they can't move around.
他们可以搬动吗？
That's the only thing they can do. Okay?
...】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】】…
Now, there are these people behind them who are like puppeteers.
...
They hold up cardboard pictures of maybe rats
他们举着纸板画的老鼠和鸟，
and birds, okay?
它们的火光投影在墙壁上。
And the fire will project these images onto the wall.
And the fire will projectthese images onto the wall.
And so these people, who again cannot move around,
好的，...
and they can only see the wall in front of them, they come to think that
...
this wall is the truth.
Okay? It's the only reality that exists.
好的？它是唯一存在的现实。
And they start naming things that
它们开始给出发见的物件进行命名。
they see, and that creates language.
它们给出发见的语言。”
And they like to play games and try to figure out
...
who can create the best language, okay?
And then they give awards to the people
...
who create the best language who are playwrights, right?
谁能制作最好的语言，演员们是吧？
Okay? So what Plato is saying is
???
that we may honor art
????
and poetry and drama, but they're all lies.
和诗歌戏剧，但都是谎言。
Okay? Now,
好的？现在，
one day, for whatever reason, we don't know why, but
一天之中，因某种缘由不知其因，才会出现。
one man finds his chains are loosened.
一人发现自己的锁链已松开。
And he's able to get up.
他能站起来。
Okay? And he swims around, and
他游动四周，
he sees a light coming from the top.
他看到光从上方照射。
So he's curious, and he climbs all the way to the top,
他好奇地爬到顶端，
and he's now outside in the free world.
他已在自由之中
Okay? And it's painful,
好的？而且很痛苦，
because his eyes are not trained to see the sunlight.
因为眼睛里没能好好看见光照。
Okay? So the sunlight, it's like burning him.
好的，光照??
Okay? It's like burning him alive.
好的？像光照在他身上照射。
And so at first, all he's doing is staring at the ground.
他好奇地爬到顶端，
And so he's seeing reflections in the pond, in the pool.
他已在自由之中
But then he slowly acclimatizes himself.
但他慢慢地适应了。
Two. And he starts to see the world around him.
两句 好 句 好句?
And it's beautiful. Okay?
他人们…
But it's so beautiful that it's beyond language.
翻译1
He doesn't have the language to describe this world that he's in.
翻译2
Okay? This is beyond language. And finally,
翻译?
he develops the courage to
他发展了勇气去
stare up in the sky, and he sees the sun.
仰望天空，看到太阳。
Okay? The sun.
好的？太阳。
And he is amazed.
他很惊喜。
He is amazed by how the sun is a source of all life.
他很惊喜的那时，太阳光照照的好像……
And now, for the first time,
]}We have to produce translations for cues [394] and [395] and [396] maybe? Wait current cues to translate: [394] And he is amazed. [395] He is amazed by... [396] And now, for thefirst time, ... The previous context shows [397] etc. So we need translations for cues 394-396. Provide array of three translations. Use simplified Chinese. Use terms: sun=太阳. Use
he fully understands the truth of the world.
]}We need to translate cues 394-396? Wait we have to produce translations for cues [394] and [5??]. Let's read carefully. The user says:
Okay? And when he does,
...
he is seized by regret, because
he remembers he has all these friends
who are still trapped and in prison in the cave.
??
And he pities them. So he swears that he will.
]}We need to…………………………………………………………………………………
Even though he. He loves where he is.
...
He will still venture back into the cave
in order to show people the truth of the world.
in order to show peoplethe truth of the world.
And to tell them that you've been living a lie all your life.
Okay? So he goes back into the cave.
好的？他回到洞穴里去。
Now remember, his eyes are now accustomed to sunlight.
现在记得，眼睛已在光照里习惯了。
So in the cave, it's all dark.
现在的眼睛已习惯光照。”
So he stumbles around. He stumbles around.
他在洞里晃动，回到回到！
He falls. And he hurts himself.
他在回到！
Okay? And then he goes and talks to the prisoners
好的？然后他去说给他人们说…
and tells them, hey.
好的，回到…
I've been to the outside world.
我去过外部世界。
I've been to the sunlight.
我去过光照
I know what truth is.
我知道真相是什么。
And then they're like, can you describe to us what it's like then?
然后他们说：你能给我们描述一下它是什么样子吗？
And he can't do it.
他能做吗？
Okay? And then they're like, tell us what you see on the wall.
OK?…
And because he's been so accustomed to truth,
因为他已习惯真理，他已能用人类语言表述一切。
he can no longer use human language to describe anything.
因为他已习惯了…
Okay? Okay? And so the people are convinced.
??
Utterly convinced. He's an idiot.
全然信服。他是个傻瓜。
He's insane. He's a clown.
他又是个疯子。又是个咬咬的咯咯！
And so they refuse to follow him.
又是个咬咬咯！
And at some point, because
在某个时刻，因
he insists on revealing the truth to them,
他坚持把真相揭示给他们，
they kill him. Okay?
他们就杀了他。
That's the allegory of the cave.
那是地坑的那条??
Okay? And you'll remember this allegory for the rest of your life.
...???????????????
Now this allegory is powerful for three reasons.
...???????
Okay? Okay? And I want you to remember these three reasons.
...???
Because we will go into them later on in the course.
The first reason is, who's the man
...???
who goes out in the sunlight and sees the truth?
谁在阳光下走出去，看到了真相？
It's obviously Socrates.
????????????????????????????????????????
Right? So with this allegory,
????????..?????..???????..????..?????..??..??..??..??..??..
Plato redeems the reputation of Socrates.
??
Right? Because remember, before, Socrates was despised.
右？因为记得，之前…
He was laughed at by the Athenians.
...
And what this allegory is saying is, that's because Socrates is a man.
和这段寓言所说的，就是因为苏格拉斯是个男人。
Socrates is a philosopher of the truth.
苏格拉斯是个真相之师
Okay? And people cannot deal with the truth.
好的？而且人们不再能处理真相。
So that's why today we celebrate Socrates as the greatest philosopher
好的，回到…
who ever lived. Not only that, but we consider him the first philosopher,
谁曾经住过。不是只此而已，先把它当作…
even though he was not the first philosopher.
...
Okay? Right?
好的？对吗？
So that's the power of the allegory of the cave.
于是这就是“井井”里那句“井”??
This image forever transforms the way humanity understands
这张图像永远变成…
and perceives Socrates.
...
That's the first thing. Second thing is,
这是第一件事，第二件事是…
this allegory becomes so powerful
]}We need to translate cue [451] and [452] into Simplified Chinese.The translation should be natural. The given translation for [451] is
that
那
in the imagination of Christians,
在宗教徒的想象中
Socrates becomes Jesus.
索福尔斯成为了…
Right? Does that make sense?
...
Socrates is Jesus for Christians.
Because Jesus was God, and
...
he came down to our world in order to speak the truth.
他来到我们的世界，传递真相。
And... Because we feared the truth, we killed him.
他因为传递传递……
Okay? So, for Christians,
?
allegory of the cave is really the story of Jesus as well.
洞穴寓言真是耶稣的故事。
Another martyr for the truth.
...
But, and the last thing is,
??
this allegory of the cave becomes the framework for Christianity.
这段洞穴寓言成为了基督教的框架。
Okay? Okay? It becomes the intellectual framework for the...
好的，...??
Religion of Christianity. So let me show you how.
...
Okay? So, this is an allegory.
好的？所以，这是一段寓言。
And behind the allegory,
而且在这段寓言之后，
there is an understanding of reality, a philosophy, a religion.
有一个理解的方位…
Okay? So here is the platonic understanding of the world.
好的？所以，这里是柏拉图式的世界观。
There's something called the form of the good.
有一个叫做“好”的形态。
Okay? And the, obviously the metaphor would be the sun.
好的？又是……】
Okay? And the form of the good is the sun.
好吧？而且好之形态是太阳。
It's a source of everything.
它是所有的源头。
Okay? It's a source of all truth.
好吧？它是所有真相的源头。
It is the truth. It's called the form of the good.
它是真相。它被称为“好”的形态。
And emanating from the form of the good are concepts
从好之形态发出的是概念与结构宇宙的理想。
and ideals that structure the universe.
And they are reason,
和它们是理
beauty, and
美丽与之
truth.
好
And justice. Okay?
和正义。好？
And there are others. Okay? But these are the main ones.
还有其他的。好？但这些是主要的。
Reason, truth, beauty, and justice.
理、真、彩、正】
They emanate from the form of the good.
它们从善的形式中发出。
Okay? And then emanating from these concepts are these forms
好的，先发出…
that are perfect.
...
Okay? So, for example, maybe the perfect horse, which represents beauty.
好的？所以，例如，可能是个好 …
Okay? Or the perfect woman, who
好的， ……
represents justice and beauty as well.
好的…
Okay? But this is all perfection.
好的？但这就是全部的完美。
And from this higher world comes...
而且从此高层世界来...
The lesser world, the reality we live in.
随后是我们所居住的更小的那一层
So everything that we see here, everything that we are here, is only an imitation.
好吧，...…
A shadow of this world.
...……
Okay? Does that make sense?
………
Imitation. So there are horses, but
模仿。于是有马，但这些马只是那儿上完美马的复制品。
these horses are just copies of that perfect horse up there.
好的，才有个别的?
Okay? So the major difference is, in this world, this world is eternal.
好的?
It has always existed, and it will always exist.
它一直存在，并且永远存在。
It's eternal. Second is,
它是永恒的。第二点是，
it is immutable.
它是不可变的。
Immutable just means it will never change.
Immutable只要说它永不变。
Okay? And the reason why is, it's perfect.
好吧，为什么又是个别的？
Okay? So these are three distinct qualities of this higher world.
好吧！
Eternal, immaculate, and perfect.
永恒、无瑕、完美。
And everything down here is basically the complete opposite.
而此处的事物则是完全相反的。
Okay? We will all die.
好吧？我们会死去。
We will all feel pain. But up there, no one feels any pain.
我们会全部感受痛苦。在此处上方，没个别的！
Okay? No one dies. It's all perfect.
好吧！ ? ? ? ? ?
Okay? Does that make sense? Guess what, guys?
…………??
What is this? This is the Christian universe.
这是什么？这就是基督教宇宙。
Right? This is God.
对吗？这就是上帝。
This is heaven. This is earth.
这就是天堂， 这就是地球。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好的？这句子句子？
This is the allegory of the cave.
...??…????????…??…??
And you can see how it does these three things.
...????……??…??
It redeems the reputation of Socrates.
它赎回了苏格拉底的声誉。
It gives Christians an understanding of Jesus.
它给了我方的思考。
And it becomes the framework from
其后又...
which Christians will build their understanding of the world.
哪位基督徒将以此为理解世界的基石。
It becomes the basis of the Christian religion.
它是基督徒的基础。”
Okay? So Plato is the real founder of the Christian religion, not Jesus.
好的，...??…??
Okay? And we will go more into this
好的？我们会更深入地讨论这个
when we discuss Christianity in the future.
当我们在未来讨论基督教时。
All right? Any questions?
好的，先问个问题。
Any questions? You look confused.
任何问题？你看起来很困惑。
Just ask any question.
只需问个问题。
Let's start having a discussion.
先开始讨论吧。
Okay? Because I know this is a lot.
好的？因为我知道这很大事。
Let's try to unpack it. Okay? Yep.
让我们来拆解一下吧。好的？
Oh, great. Okay. Very public.
哦，太好了，先说吧。
Okay. So
好的。于是[534] 于是，[535]《共和国》其实不只是关于洞穴寓言。[536] 好的？《洞穴寓言》也在《...】}{
the Republic isn't really about the allegory of the cave.
?}We need to produce translations for cues [534],[535],[536] in order. The previous context: [534] Okay. So [535] the Republic isn't really... [536] Okay? The allegory of the cave actually appears in the Republic. We need totranslate each cue into Simplified Chinese. Use given terms. Provide JSON array translations. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Should be natural Chinese subtitle lines. Let's craft translations: [534]
Okay? The allegory of the cave actually appears in the Republic.
Actually [534] is
The Republic itself,
好的？《共和国》本身，
Plato is trying to answer the question,
帕洛特尝试回答问题，
what is a good society?
什么是好事物？
Okay? What is a good society?
好的？什么是好社会？
That's the question he's trying to answer.
这是他要回答的问题。
Because it's clearly not democracy. Because democracy kills Socrates.
因为它明显不是民主。
Okay? So it's clearly not democracy.
好的？所以它明显不是民主。
So what makes a good society?
那么什么是好社会？
And the answer is, a society that is not a good society.
答案是：一个不好的社会。
It's a society that's based on justice.
它是一个以正义为基础的社会。
Okay? It's a society that's based on justice.
它是一个以正义为基础的句子。
But then what is justice? It's truth.
它是一个以正义的句子。
Okay? But then what's truth?
OK?
Well, truth is the form of the good.
好的！
Then what's the form of the good? It is the thing
...
that philosophers can access for their own reasoning.
那位哲学家可用来做自我推理的那点
Right? Right? Therefore,
]}{
a good society is one that is ruled.
一个好社会是由哲学家统治的。
By philosopher kings.
由哲学之王统领
Because they're the only ones who can access the truth.
因为他们才是能接触真理的人。
Okay? And this society that's perfect, he calls the Republic.
好的，~！
That's why it's called the Republic. The Republic, and
...
we'll read this again next semester is,
我们会在下个学期再读一遍。
it's really trying to figure out what makes a good society.
...
Okay? And to further his argument,
Plato uses the allegory of the cave.
Plato 记得?
And like, listen.
...
Fifty years from now. You will still remember the allegory of the cave.
五十年后，随时记得? ！
Maybe you won't remember the Charles Socrates or anything else you've learned in this class.
...
But you will definitely remember the allegory of the cave.
但你一定会记得洞穴寓言。
Okay? Because it's embedded. First of all, it's a beautiful metaphor.
好的，先说一段话！
But it's also embedded in our society.
但也在我们...??
Okay? So,
? 1???????????????..???
does that answer your question, Echo?
做了就能回答你的问题，回声？
Yeah. Do you have more questions?
是的！...
All right. Okay. So, something else I want to explain is, okay.
好的。好了。 于是我想说的就是…
Some might be interested as to why Plato is considered the greatest philosopher of all time.
有点儿…
Okay? All right.
好的？好吧。
So, it's not because he's the best.
于是，刚好是...
All right? It's not because he's the best.
好的？不是因为他是最好的。
I would say there are three good reasons why he's so influential today.
我会说有三点好理由能让他今天能很大影响。
The first is Plato,
第一个是柏拉图，
the way he writes.
它的写作方式…
It's unique and original to him.
...
Plato originally trained as a playwright.
柏拉图最初是戏剧作家。
Okay? So, he wanted to be Ischilus.
好吧？他想成为伊斯库鲁斯。
He wanted to be Sophocles. Eupatius.
他想要演出苏菲克斯·尤帕斯。
Because everyone wanted to be a playwright in Athens.
因为大家都想在雅典成为剧作家。
It was the highest honor. So,
它是最高的荣誉。
he learned the art of dialogue.
他学会了对话语的练习
Okay? Because dialogue is the basis for theater.
好吧？因为对话是戏剧的基础。
And so, what he did that was innovative, and no one did this before,
而且他所作的就是创新之作，且是先前无人所作。
was he basically took the dialogue of the stage.
他把舞台的对话写成了
And he transferred onto the stage.
他把舞台搬到舞台上。
So, when you read Plato, it's actually a lot of fun.
当你读《柏拉图》时，能有多好玩！
Okay? Because it's basically Socrates, his main character,
他在此时刻…
having arguments and conversations with other people.
拥有与他人辩论与对话。
So, in terms of readability,
在可读性方面，
Plato is definitely probably one of the most readable philosophers.
柏拉图大概是可读性最好的哲学家之一。
Okay? He's definitely the most readable famous philosopher.
好的？他绝对是最易读的名哲学家。
Later on in the semester, we will talk about Immanuel Kant
稍后学期中，我们会谈到伊曼努尔·康德和黑格尔。
and Hegel.
And they are not readable. Okay?
翻译1
But Plato, anyone can read Plato and enjoy Plato.
]}We need to translate cues 599-601. Provide array of translations. Each string may contain newline. Let's translate: 599:
Okay? So, his readability,
. Wait cue 599:
the originality of his writing is
...
one really good reason why he remains
so popular today.
...
Second is he
第二个是他
is extremely anti -democratic.
他很大方的很大方的
Okay? His thinking is...
好的，??
Because, like, remember, the most traumatic event in his life was the death of his mentor,
因为...记得...他最重要的事件是他导师的去世
Socrates. And so, it's the Athenian democracy who killed his mentor.
...
So, he passionately hates democracy.
Okay? Well, you know who else hates democracy?
...
Kings hate democracy. And throughout most of human history,
王子们...
kings ruled the world. Right?
...
So, what's amazing about Plato is he's the only writer in human history
所以，柏拉图的事物很有意思，...
who has ever been a writer. He's the only writer in human history who has been a writer continuously for 2,000 years.
...
Does that make sense? We lost Homer for a bit.
616. 译文：...?
We lost the playwrights,
]}We need to translate cues 616 and 617. Provide JSON array translations. Let's translate:
Aeschylus, Sophocles, and Eupatius for a long time.
阿谢尔·欧菲尔·尤帕提斯在很久的时间里...
But Plato has always been read continuously.
但...
And he's been the most...
...
And as a result, because it's easy to access Plato,
翻译结果
he's become the most influential philosopher of all time.
...
Okay? Does that make sense? And
OK? 这………………………………………………
third of all was his academy.
??
Okay? And the academy in Athens at
好的，...
that time, it's like Harvard, right?
that time, it'slike Harvard, right?
Or Oxford today. It's a place where
...
all the elite children went.
所有精英孩子都去过。
Okay? So, his students were the most powerful people in the world basically.
好的？所以，他的学生基本上是世界上最有权势的人。
And his most famous student was Aristotle.
和他的最著名学生是亚里士多德。
And as we'll discuss in future classes,
]}We need to translate cues [630] and [631] into Simplified Chinese. Provide JSON with translations array. Each translation string may contain at most one newline. Use preferred terms. For [630]
Aristotle is the one who basically...
Aristotle...??
packaged and promoted Greek culture. And
]}We need to translate [632] and [??]. The earlier? The???????? etc…We must…………………………………………??………??… English?………..?………..?…………………………i..……………………??……………………{
Plato became a very important
Plato...???
individual in the spreading of Greek culture.
??
In fact, he was basically the main hero in this process.
???
Okay? So, does that make sense?
?
All right? Feel free to argue with me, by the way.
All right? 让我来给我...??
I mean, like, if you feel I've said anything controversial or you sort of disagree with,
???..???????????..????????..??…??…??…??…??…??…??..??……..??…..??………..??……..??…
let me know. And I will rebut.
让我知道。然后我会反驳。
We can have a psychotic dialogue.
我们可以进行一次心理对话。
Okay? Any more questions?
好的，接着再问个问题。
Ask a question. Okay.
}]}
That's a good question. Okay?
???
What are the influences of Plato?
]}We need to translate cues 644 and 645. Provide JSON with translations array. Use simplified Chinese. Use terms. Let's translate: 644:
Okay? So, you can make the argument that
...
Socrates was not that
Socrates was notthat
much of an intellectual influence on Plato.
And the reason why is, remember,
...
Socrates questioned your wisdom.
??
But he himself did not propose any of his own theories.
...
Okay? So... Right.
好的？所以……好吧。
So, what we know is this.
...
First of all, during this time,
首先，在这段时间里，
this was the golden age of Greek philosophy.
这是个好句子
Right? And at that time, you had lots of philosophers in different policies,
好吧？那时你有许多哲学家在不同的政策、不同的地方，提出这些精彩的理论。
different places, proposing all these wonderful theories.
好吧？那时你有许多哲学家在不同的政策…
So Plato definitely had access to them.
所以柏拉图肯定有机会接触它们。
Plus, they were all friends.
再加上他们都相互相通。”
Okay? And
好的？和
we also know this world of Greek thought was heavily influenced by Egypt.
我们也知道希腊的思维世界受埃及之影响很大。
Right? Because Egypt was really the epicenter of learning
好的，先前………………
and philosophy at this time.
...
And Egypt was actually very close to Greece.
埃及实际上与希腊相近。
Also, Mesopotamia.
又是美索波特米亚。
Right? The Persians.
对的？波斯人。
Okay? So, 399 B.C.
好的？399 B.C.
Socrates dies. And then Plato spends the next 12 years traveling around the world.
苏格拉底去世。随后柏拉多在接下来12年里游历四方。
And while he's traveling, he's absorbing lots of different philosophy.
...
Okay? So, look.
We don't have access to Egyptian sources. Right? So
...
we don't know what sources would influence Plato.
But we know the Egyptians heavily influenced him.
...
And we know the Greeks. So we can make the assumption that
the Egyptians were heavily influenced on Plato.
...
As well as Mesopotamia.
As well as the other Greek philosophers like Pythagoras
...
and Democritus.
和德谟克利特斯。
And so
而且如此
what's really important is Athens at this time was not an isolated society.
在此时的雅典，真正重要的是它不是一个独立的社会。
It was part of a larger intellectual landscape.
它是更大知识景观的一部分。
And a lot of these places had richer intellectual histories than Athens.
并且有许多的那种地方有更丰富的知识历史。
Okay? Egypt definitely. Mesopotamia.
好的？ 以此为例，埃及之中…
Okay? So does that answer your question?
好的？ 那么这回答了你的问题吗？
The answer is we don't know. Okay? And the reason, again, is most of this is lost to us.
好的，回到…………………
Right? I'm sure there were philosophers at this time
?
who were the equal of Plato in terms of originality.
谁是柏拉图原创性方面的等价者。
Okay? But we don't know who these people were.
好的，...??
Because remember, citizenship, it's not really just about changing the past.
因为...??
It's also about improving the past.
...
Okay? Eliminating most of the past.
OK?
Right? Okay? .
??
..
..??
...
.....
..
??
....
...
................ of Syracuse invited Plato to come counsel
him on how to be a tyrant, a good tyrant, right?
He wanted to be like a philosopher king.
翻译1
And then Plato basically said to him, well, you should let me be the king,
翻译2
and then you will have a philosopher king.
译文1
And of course, the king of Syracuse didn't like this idea, so
译前
he almost killed Plato, okay?
译文1
But Plato had very, again, Plato has very wealthy friends,
译前
and he was very rich himself, so he basically ransomed his way out of Syracuse.
翻译1
So as a politician,
翻译2
as a practitioner of philosophy,
作为哲学实践者，
he's terrible, okay?
他很糟糕，OK吗？
Right? He tried his philosophy in Syracuse, didn't work out, pissed off a lot of people,
713. 右? 先后? 先后?? 先后?? 先后?? 译?? 先后?? ?? 先后?? 先后?? 1?? 先后?? 句?? 先后?? 1?? 1?? 1?? 句..?? ?? 希尔? 先后?? 希尔? 1..?? ?? 1..?? ?? ?? 翻译?? ?? 1..?? 2..?? ?? JSON...
okay? But
]}We need to translate cues 713 and 714. Provide JSON arraytranslations. Use simplified Chinese. Let's translate: 713:
everyone wanted to be a philosopher king.
...
Any more questions?
???
Okay. So
next class we will do
???
The Rise of Macedonia, okay?
So remember, these are ideas that
记住， 这些是 这时在雅典和希腊的 词句…
are being incubated in Athens and in Greece at this time.
...
But ultimately, these ideas conquer the world, right?
但最终，这些思想征服了世界，对吧？
Greek theater, Greek philosophy spread all around the world.
希腊戏剧、希腊哲学遍布全球。
And the main reason is Macedonia.
726 … ? … ? … ?… ?? ?? ??…
The main reason are two individuals,
? ???…
Philip II of Macedonia and Alexander the Great, okay?
菲利普二世·马其达王与亚历山大大帝，好的？
Who together will create the Hellenistic Empire.
谁会把………
And this is why Greek culture will spread around the world
译文1
and become the basis of Western civilization.
译句